<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syahrul Anuar</title>
    <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Syahrul Anuar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://syahrulanuar.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>I am open to collaborations and research. Feel free to reach out on any of the channels below.
Contact Me See What&amp;rsquo;s Up Collect! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:27:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Syahrul Anuar (b. 1995 Singapore) is a cultural worker aligning closely to the notions of merantau (migration), owing to his family’s diaspora within the Nusantara (Malay World). Intrigued by the narratives and histories within the Nusantara, he surveys, unravels and weaves the complexities and multiplicities of how humans consume and depict it, employing a research-based methodology with both facts and fiction, and the past and present. His practice constantly expands beyond the photographic; recently utilising AI and ML methods and frameworks, questioning the role of photography in today’s landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background Noise</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/backgroundnoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/backgroundnoise/</guid>
      <description>Background Noise 2019 Max MSP, Ableton Live, Uncompressed Audio Files Visual Scores (in order)
 DSC_0561 DSC_2213 DSC_2208 DSC_2211 DSC_1044 DSC_1031  It is estimated that only 4% of Singapore is in total darkness. Light pollution exists as a paradox in Singapore, where it allows us to see at night yet blinding us from seeing the stars glittered across the sky.
Background Noise is a series of photographic images, that employs the digital camera as a means to interrogate light pollution in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Works</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/commercial/</guid>
      <description>I am a trained photographer and a self-taught developer, focusing on front-end and Machine Learning applications.
My CV and Photography Portfolio is upon reqeust only. Kindly request it here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Is When?</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/nowiswhen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/nowiswhen/</guid>
      <description>Now Is When? 2020 2-Channel Video Projection 15:24 Minutes Now Is When? investigates into the metaphorical and materiality of granite which is imbued with histories and narratives — of the factual and fictional and of the past and present.
Granite has served as foundational building blocks for our nation-building — excavated locally and becoming a crucial resource for public housing alongside protecting our coastlines from erosion. Land scarcity, usage and raw materials remains as a key concern in our state policies and agendas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tanah Di Bawah Angin</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/tanahdibawahangin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/tanahdibawahangin/</guid>
      <description>Tanah Di Bawah Angin (The Land Beneath The Wind) 2021 3-channel Video, DCGAN images on Fine Art Photographic Paper, Teak Dresser Tanah Di Bawah Angin is a visual exercise in various parts, to simultaneously mend and dissect the various viscosities of Malay mythical tales with the factual occurrences of the Straw-headed Bulbul within the Nusantara (The Malay World). The Straw-headed Bulbul is a recurring oral motif in the Nusantara and is at high risk of facing extinction in Southeast Asia — poached and hunted for its beautiful call and song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yang Pertama Dan Utama</title>
      <link>https://syahrulanuar.org/yangpertamadanutama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syahrulanuar.org/yangpertamadanutama/</guid>
      <description>Yang Pertama Dan Utama (The First &amp;amp; Foremost) 2021 A2 Digital Prints on Fine Art Photographic Paper Yang Pertama Dan Utama (The First And Foremost) playfully investigates the dichotomies of photographic representations to a lived experience at the artist’s first home along the stretch at Jalan Satu.
The photographic series deals with the photographic materiality of the hoarding images which were printed on vinyl. These hoarding images which present idealistic and picturesque families are posed, fabricated and composited; brings to light notions of representations in photography.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
